When we talk about biodynamic embryology, the therapist will give very little
induction.
But we will trust something beyond ourselves.
Not giving, not inducing, is quite complicated because we have been taught the opposite.
And secondly, we are not just in contact with tissue; we are in contact with the space that
surrounds us.
This notion is quite important to understand and to realize from the depth of yourself
to what...
is impossible to achieve.
This leads to an important concept.
We need to differentiate between what we call primary respiration and primary
respiratory movement.
This primary respiration is present everywhere.
It is not something that exists only in the body; it is something
that is present in totality.
A synonym would be the breath of life.
So we will need to experience this, to dare to enter into that space.
We come to work on embryology.
And one of the great principles of osteopathy is that the body has an ability
for self-regulation and a homeostatic principle, a principle of health.
So we will work within this principle of biodynamics with health
and not against disease.
It is a switch that most of the time, we look for a lesion and I will suggest
looking for health.
This is not easy because we are quickly attracted to the lesion.
We will not disregard it either, the secret to
entering this process
is to discover what neutrality is. So first, there is what we call the practitioner’s neutral,
which is not obvious because most of the time we are not
in neutral.
I have always encouraged a little meditation, introducing you gradually to a
possibility of moving
towards a state
of neutrality. The therapist’s neutral does not yet allow for
the emergence
of this therapeutic power, it does not yet allow for fully expressing the breath of life,
thus the primary respiration. Initially, the
practitioner needs to have a centered state and discover a state of
neutral. Once we have discovered this state of neutral and we
come into contact
with the patient, we must open our space.
to the different fields, zone A, which is the body, zone B,
on which I will insist a lot throughout this seminar in the fluidic system,
zone B, then the space in which we are,
and finally, we will go into the different spaces up to
the image you can hold.
The therapist's neutral, centered, neutral, and the second thing, and
this is the second thing,
difficulty, we need to bring forth the neutral in the patient. That is the
key, in fact. You have
your own neutral, but if the patient does not enter into their own neutral,
that is, into a
disengagement, we cannot reveal the therapeutic forces. They emerge
when there is
a meeting of these two neutrals to form the
1, the 2 we could say, to form the whole we call the
3. When you have the meeting of the therapist's neutral with
the patient's neutral, the
therapeutic forces, thus the primary respiration, breath of life, allows
the inherent power of the
system to emerge in its force and originality.
This is where we have this
encounter with the embryonic forces; it is the same energy that the body
will seek
to regenerate and thus restructure
and regain function.
We will notice that you gradually need to bring people back down to
Earth.
This is what we call the force of gravity.
When I am well grounded in gravity, I am well connected to the Earth.
And this connection to the Earth is very important.
There are people who are too grounded; they are already buried.
There are people who are not...
on the Earth. They float. They are completely there. In fact, we need to restore that connection.
That is the force of gravity. Then, there is another force that will bring,
which is
what we call the electromagnetic force. It is about bringing people back into their bodies.
If you have had whiplash, for example, or accidents, you may be outside yourself.
We don't see it like this, but these people are outside of their bodies. And it is about bringing
them back into the electromagnetic field. The third thing is...
bringing people back into their energetic body, into the atmos.
In the atmos, it means in the formless.
What you can feel when it is an energetic body,
you will perceive it as a vibrational state.
It is a frequency, it is a vibration.
The fourth thing will be bringing people into their body of light.
When you are fully luminous, you are fully in your function.
So that means bringing people into their function.
The more you are in this, the more you will...
attract the right energy around you. The more you will attract what I call the
right synchronicities. To reach this level, we need what we call
the meeting point, a point of encounter between the therapist and the patient.
If there is
no meeting point, if there is no point of encounter, there is no emergence.
There are patients where you can perform a treatment, but there was no point of meeting.
In fact, not much will happen.
You enter, and you already know what you will do.
There is no point of meeting.
The important thing is to discover this neutral,
to bring forth this neutral in your patient.
But for that, we need this space.
And therefore, we need to be attentive to the possibility of this emergence.
Through touch, through presence.
Through leveling, whenever I have a child, I
will lower myself to the child’s level.
I will look for a point of meeting.
And if this point of meeting happens, the child quickly enters
the emergence of their neutral.
And when I have this emergence, then the therapeutic force can
begin to express itself.
So we don’t impose; we seek the neutral.
We seek the patient’s neutral.
We surrender to something I call the laws of nature.
It is quite important to have this notion of trust in this process.
In these movements that will arise through your presence,
there will be corrections that will occur.
And these corrections are what Sutherland described,
which is close, in fact, to these biodynamic movements
found in embryonic developmental motility.
That will be tomorrow.
Things that are going to happen. The first thing that is very important is to restart this
longitudinal fluctuation. It is one of the first powers that the body will use. And if you study
a little about Sutherland, he talks about that. Furthermore, when he works at the base,
or he is going to work at that level, to reinvigorate this longitudinal fluctuation.
I reiterate once again, what is your neutral? And I will ask you this
question for you; what is neutral? Because it is from this neutral that
we will work. This is where the Chinese
have a wonderful word
called
wuwei. It does not mean
doing nothing,
it means non-doing.
That is very different.
The notion of doing nothing
and non-doing.
Wuwei.
There are people who only use
their knowledge,
and there are people who use...
more their imagination. I will ask you to use both. We
need
that knowledge, your background. We need
that imagination and to
put them together to gradually work with that.